Swedish-Yugoslavian Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Swedish-Yugoslavian Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 25
Yale University Arts Library
3.33
8 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of paintings from Sweden, Switzerland and the former Yugoslavia [now Serbia and Montenegro].Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of paintings from Sweden, Switzerland and the former Yugoslavia [now Serbia and Montenegro]. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Painting -- Sweden; Painting -- Switzerland; Painting -- Yugoslavia; Painting -- Serbia and Montenegro; Photography of art; Photographs; Reproductions
- Sweden.
  - Anonymous., 2 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 7 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - Blomquist, Gunilla, and Hammarberg, Jorgen, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Fahlstrom, Oyvind, 1928-., 2 (Box 1)
    - Fonssagrives-Penn, Lisa, 1911-1992., 1 (Box 1)
    - Hesselbom, Otto, 1848-1913., 1 (Box 1)
    - Hullgren, Oscar, 1869-1948., 1 (Box 1)
    - Johansson, Arvid, 1862-1923., 1 (Box 1)
    - Lavreince, Nicholas, 1737-1807., 1 (Box 1)
    - Pasch, Lorenzo the Younger, 1733-1805., 1 (Box 1)
    - Percy, Arthur C., 1886-., 1 (Box 1)
    - Schjerbecki, Helene, XX C., 1 (Box 1)
    - Simonsson, Birger, 1883-., 1 (Box 1)
    - Strindberg, August, 1849-1910., 3 (Box 1)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 118 (Box 1)
    - Albertus Pictor, XV C., 11 (Box 1)
    - Bjorck, Oscar, 1860-1929., 1 (Box 1)
    - Carlsund, Otto G., 1897-1948., 7 (Box 1)
    - Dahl, Michael, 1656-1743., 3 (Box 1)
    - Eggeling, Viking, 1880-1925., 4 (Box 1)
    - Engstrom, Leander, 1886-1927., 1 (Box 1)
    - Eugen Napoleon Nicolaus, prince, 1865-1947., 2 (Box 1)
    - Fougstedt, Arvid, 1888-1929., 1 (Box 1)
    - Larsson, Carl, 1853-1919., 24 (Box 1)
    - Liljefors, Bruno, 1860-1939., 7 (Box 1)
    - Notke, Bernt, 1440-1509., 3 (Box 1)
    - Rosenroth, Johannes, XV C., 2 (Box 1)
    - Wallin, David, 1876-., 1 (Box 1)
    - Wilhelmson, Carl, 1866-1928., 4 (Box 1)
    - Zorn, Anders L., 1860-1920., 47 (Box 2)
- Switzerland (Box 2)
  - Anonymous., 9 (Box 2)
    - XII Century., 6 (Box 2)
    - XV Century., 1 (Box 2)
    - XVII Century., 1 (Box 2)
    - XVIII Century., 1 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 55 (Box 2)
    - Amiet, Cuno, 1868-1961., 1 (Box 2)
    - Auberjonois, Rene, 1872-1957., 1 (Box 2)
    - Bernasconi, Livio, XX C., 1 (Box 2)
    - Berthoud, Leon, 1822-1892., 1 (Box 2)
    - Biedermann, J.J., 1763-1830., 1 (Box 2)
    - Burnand, Eugene, 1850-1921., 1 (Box 2)
    - Castelli, Luciano, 1951-., 1 (Box 2)
      Work done with Rainer Fettting and Salome.
    - Castres, E., 1838-1902., 1 (Box 2)
    - Chinet, Charles, XX C., 1 (Box 2)
    - Crotti, Jean, 1878-1958., 1 (Box 2)
    - Dietler, J. F., 1804-1874., 1 (Box 2)
    - Ferriere, F., 1752-1839., 1 (Box 2)
    - Fisher, Hans, 1907-., 1 (Box 2)
    - Fregevize, Frederic, 1776-1849., 1 (Box 2)
    - Gessner, Salomon, 1730-1788., 1 (Box 2)
    - Giacometti, Augusto, 1877-1947., 1 (Box 2)
    - Glarner, Fritz, 1899-., 1 (Box 2)
    - Grob, Konrad, 1828-1904., 1 (Box 2)
    - Heinz, Joseph, 1564-1609., 1 (Box 2)
    - Hermanjat, Jacques Elie Abraham, 1862-1932., 1 (Box 2)
    - Hinterreiter, Hans, 1902-., 1 (Box 2)
    - Hug, Charles, 1899-., 1 (Box 2)
    - Itten, Johannes, 1888-1967., 1 (Box 2)
    - Leu, Hans the Youngr, 1490-1531., 2 (Box 2)
    - Lindtmayer, Daniel, 1552-1606., 2 (Box 2)
    - Liner, Carl, 1871-1946., 1 (Box 2)
    - Meuron, Max de, 1785-1868., 1 (Box 2)
    - Meyer-Amden, Otto, 1885-1932., 1 (Box 2)
    - Monay, Ywon, XX C., 1 (Box 2)
    - Pfister, Albert, 1884-1978., 1 (Box 2)
    - Rossi, Luigi, 1853-1923., 1 (Box 2)
    - Schawinsky, Xanti (Alexander), 1904-1979., 2 (Box 2)
    - Schneider, Gerard, 1896-1986., 1 (Box 2)
    - Seligmann, Kurt, 1900-1962., 2 (Box 2)
    - Stabli, Adolf, 1843-1901., 1 (Box 3)
    - Steffan, Johann Gottfried, 1815-1905., 1 (Box 3)
    - Stimmer, Tobias, 1539-1589., 2 (Box 3)
    - Taeuber-Arp, Sophie, 1889-1943., 3 (Box 3)
    - Terbois, Pierre, XX C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Tinguely, Jean, 1925-., 1 (Box 3)
    - Tsharner, Johann von, 1886-., 1 (Box 3)
    - Vallet, Edouard, 1876-., 2 (Box 3)
    - Waser, Anna, 1678-1714., 1 (Box 3)
    - Wegmann, Karl Jacob, 1928-., 1 (Box 3)
    - Welti, Albert, 1862-1912., 1 (Box 3)
    - Wuilleret, Pierre, 1580-1643., 1 (Box 3)
    - Ziegler, Christian von, XVIII C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Zund, Robert, 1827-1909., 1 (Box 3)
  - Individual Artists, A-Z., 413 (Box 3)
    - Agasse, Jacques-Laurent, 1767-1849., 11 (Box 3)
    - Anker, Albert, 1831-1910., 7 (Box 3)
    - Bieler, Ernest, active 1884-., 2 (Box 3)
    - Bill, Max, 1908-., 5 (Box 3)
    - Bock, Hans the Elder, c.1550-1623., 9 (Box 3)
    - Buchser, Frank, 1828-1890., 4 (Box 3)
    - Calame, Alexander, 1810-1864., 8 (Box 3)
    - Erni, Hans, 1909-., 3 (Box 3)
    - Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966., 22 (Box 3)
    - Hodler, Ferdinand, 1853-1918., 42 (Box 4)
    - Klee, Paul, 1879-1940., 236 (Box 4)
      - Undated works., 41 (Box 4)
      - Works from before 1900., 1 (Box 4)
      - Works from 1900-1919., 22 (Box 5)
      - Works from 1920-1924., 53 (Box 5)
      - Works from 1925-1929., 33 (Box 6)
      - Works from 1930-1934., 44 (Box 6)
      - Works from 1935-1939., 34 (Box 7)
      - Works from 1940 on., 8 (Box 7)
    - Koller, Rudolf, 1828-1905., 2 (Box 7)
    - Liotard, Jean Etienne, 1702-1789., 20 (Box 7)
    - Menn, Barthelemy, 1815-1893., 2 (Box 7)
    - Robert, Leopold, 1794-1835., 5 (Box 7)
    - Rudisuhli, Eduard, 1875-., 2 (Box 7)
    - Stuckelberg, Ernst, 1831-1903., 4 (Box 8)
    - Topffer, W. A., 1766-1847., 1 (Box 8)
    - Vallotton, Felix, 1865-1925., 25 (Box 8)
    - Wolff, Caspar, 1735-1798., 3 (Box 8)
- Yugoslavia. (Box 8)
  - Anonymous., 44 (Box 8)
    - Before XII Century., 1 (Box 8)
    - XII Century., 7 (Box 8)
    - XIII Century., 15 (Box 8)
    - XIV Century., 12 (Box 8)
    - XV through XVIII Century., 9 (Box 8)
  - Artists Known A-Z., 5 (Box 8)
    - Barilli, Milena, 1912-., 1 (Box 8)
    - Ilic, Boza, XX Century., 1 (Box 8)
    - Jurjev, Blaz, XV or XVI C., 1 (Box 8)
    - Mestrovic, Ivan, XX C., 1 (Box 8)
    - Mitrofanovic, Georgije, XVII C., 1 (Box 8)